我们该告诉瑞秋
Should we tell Rachel
她隔壁就有一间单人待产室吗
there's an empty private room right next door to hers?
可以啊  或者我们可以在这里做爱
We could. Or we could have sex in it.
让我边脱裤子边想吧
Well, let me think about that while I remove my pants!
好了  先生  为我播种吧
Okay, mister! Fertilize me!
那是珍妮丝的声音吗
Does that sound like Janice?
如果不是她  那就是个很像她的人
If it's not, then there's two of them.
而那表示世界末日到了
And that would mean it's the end of the world!
我不敢相信要拖这么久 你还好吗
I can't believe this is taking so long. How you doing?
还不错  你知道想使劲把圣柏纳犬
Not bad. You know that feeling, when you trying to
从屁股里拉出来的感觉吗
blow a Saint Bernard out your ass?
真是太奇怪了  我好像听到...
Weirdest thing. Did I hear...?
天啊  是真的
Mother of God, it's true!
钱德勒`宾
Chandler Bing!
珍妮丝
Janice.
不只是那样  珍妮丝要生了
Not just Janice. Janice in labor.
她在经历阵痛什么的
Contracting and everything.
生孩子对我来说很容易  我的骨盆很宽
Oh, this should be easy. I have a very wide pelvis.
你应该记得  钱德勒
You remember, Chandler.
珍妮丝  我都不知道你怀孕了
Janice, I didn't even know you were pregnant.
你偷走了哪个笨蛋的"精"华
Who's the unwitting human whose essence you've stolen?
是你
It's you.
这是你的孩子
This is yours.
什么
What?
看他有多紧张
Look how nervous he gets!
我们都好几年没上过床了
We haven't slept together in years!
那可真搞笑  会痛吗  生孩子会痛吗
That's funny. Does it hurt ? Does the labor hurt?
好吧  我想到一个
Okay, I've got one for you.
如果非吃不可  你要吃哪一个
If you had to, which would you rather eat?
千里眼的小狗还是会说话的猩猩
A Seeing Eye dog or a talking gorilla?
我要选会说话的猩猩
I'd have to say the talking gorilla.
因为至少我可以跟它解释是你逼我吃掉它的
Because at least I could explain to him that you're making me eat him.
-某人念过大学哦  -对
- Oh. Somebody went to college. - Yeah.
怎么了  对不起
Wow. What is it? I'm sorry.
对不起  我的脚好痒
I'm sorry. My foot itches like crazy.
让我来吧
Oh. I'll get it.
通常我跟女人混熟之后
I usually get to know a girl better
才会让她用汤匙帮我搔痒
before I let her spoon me.
别激动  我们又不是要用"插"子
Relax. It's not like we're forking.
这都第五个了  罗期
Oh, that's five, Ross.
五个女人生了五个孩子
Five women have had five babies...
我还是没生
...and I have had no babies.
她为什么不肯出来
Why doesn't she want to come out?
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I think it is?
我想九个月来
I think you made such a nice home for her
她在你的身体里住得很舒服  所以不想离开
over the last nine months that she just doesn't want to leave.
你甚至在瞎掰哄我
Look at you making up crap for me.
-天啊  -好吧
- Oh, God. - Okay. Okay.
21个小时了  你简直是英雄
Twenty-one hours. You're a hero.
医生  你得想想办法  给我用药吧
Doctor, you gotta do something! Get me drugs...
或是放火把她熏出来
...or light a fire up in there and just smoke it out!
事实上  我想你可以进产房了
Actually, I think you're ready to go to the delivery room.
什么
What?
开了10公分了  你快当妈妈了
Ten centimeters. You're about to become a mom.
天啊  好吧
Oh, my God. Okay.
打败你了  逊鬼
Beat you, sucker!
天啊  他就是刚刚来看过我的医生
Oh, my God! That's the doctor who was in my room before.
好吧  幻想先生
Okay, Mr. Percocet.
我跟你说  电视里的那个人刚刚来过
I'm telling you, the guy from that show was here..
还问了我一堆怪问题
in my room asking me all these weird questions.
克利夫  你真的相信电视明星
Cliff, do you really believe that a character from a TV show
来过你的房间
was here in your room?
瑞秋要生了
Rachel's having her baby!
就是他  你认识他吗
That's him! You know him?
好吧  我...好吧
Okay. Okay. I... Okay.
我派我朋友乔伊来调查你
I sent my friend, Joey, in here to find out stuff about you.
如果有帮助的话
If it... You know, if it helps,
我们觉得你是个好人
you came off great.
比现在的我好多了
A lot better than I'm coming off right now.
我不敢相信你要他假扮医生
I don't believe this. You got him to pretend he was some fake doctor?
假扮  对不起  看这里
Fake? Excuse me? Hello?
你还要我以为自己疯了
And then you tried making me think I was crazy?
那样是不对的  我非常抱歉
Right. That was wrong. I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
那只是因为我非常喜欢你
It's just that I liked you so much.
我们能重新开始吗
Can we just start over?
我觉得不行
I don't think so.
我可以说话吗  你跟我透露了很多你的私事
If I may? You told me a lot of personal stuff about you, right?
或许你应该知道一些关于她的私事
Now, maybe it would help if you knew some personal stuff about her.
她曾跟男同志冰舞选手结婚
She was married to a gay ice dancer.
她帮她弟弟生下三胞胎
She gave birth to her brother's triplets.
她的双胞胎姐姐曾是A片女优
Her twin sister used to do porn.
-乔伊  你简直是越抹越黑  -对
- Joey, we're trying to dial down the crazy. - Right.
我们对彼此并不太了解
We don't really know each other,
要忘记这次相遇很容易
so it'd be easy to forget about this...
但我们对彼此都有感觉
...but there's something between us.
我不知道你是怎么样...
I don't know about you...
但我不常有这种奇妙邂逅
...but that doesn't happen to me a lot.
-我也是  -我也是
- It doesn't happen to me either. - Me neither!
用力  你得再用力五秒
Push. Push. We're gonna push for five more seconds.
五  四...
Five, four...
三  二  一
Three, two, one! Oh!
下一次阵痛是20秒后
The next contraction should be in about 20 seconds.
-我没办法再用力了  -你表现得很好
- I can't push any more! - You're doing great.
天啊  这根本就不到20秒嘛
Oh, God! Twenty seconds, my ass!
来吧  继续用力
Here we go. Okay, keep pushing.
-来吧  -用力  等一下
- Come on. - Push. Wait.
我看到了什么
I see something.
什么  真的吗  我的天啊
What, you do? You do? Oh, my God!
-别说"我的天啊"  什么  -那是什么
- Don't say "Oh, my God!" What?! - What is that?
宝宝的屁股  她倒位了
The baby's buttocks. She's breech.
-我还以为她有两个头  -天啊
- I thought she had two heads. - Oh, God!
她没事吧
Is she gonna be okay?
-她没事的  -好吧
- She's gonna be fine. - Okay.
她的胎位不正
She's in a more difficult position,
你得更加用力才行
so you have to push harder now, go, push.
-好吧  -就是那样  用力
- Okay. - That's it. Push. Push.
瑞秋  你得更用力  还没有任何变化
Rachel, you're gonna have to push even harder. Nothing is happening.
抱歉  我办不到
I'm sorry, I can't! I can't!
不  我知道你办得到  加油
Yes, you can. I know you can do this. Let's go.
我不知道咋办  拜托  帮我用力吧
I had no idea. Please, you do it for me!
来吧  再来一次
Let's go. One more time.
最后一次  准备好了吗
One final push, ready?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
很好
Good.
继续用力
Keep pushing!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你不知道那有多痛
You have no idea how much this hurts.
继续用力
Keep going! Keep going!
好了
Here we go!
宝宝胎位不正  但她要出来了
She's upside down, but she's coming!
-天啊  -我的天啊
- Oh, God! - Oh! Oh, my God!
天啊  她出来了
Oh, my God, she's here.
她太完美了
Oh, she's perfect.
哇  她好小啊
Oh, wow! Oh, she's so tiny.
她要去哪里
Where'd she go?
他们得先把她包起来
They're just wrapping her up.
好吧  小心一点  她真的很小
Okay. Well, be careful with her, she's really tiny.
宝宝来喽
Here she is.
你好呀
Hey, you.
谢谢你终于出来了
Oh, thanks for coming out of me.
我知道
I know. Oh.
她在看我
She's looking at me.
嗨  我认识你
Hi. I know you.
-你们取好名字了吗  -还没有
- Do we have a name yet? - No, not yet.
没关系  先叫她格林之女
That's fine. For now we'll just call her Baby Girl Greene.
不  盖勒·格林之女
Oh, no. Baby Girl Geller-Greene.
你好  小姑娘
Hello, Baby Girl.
-我们能进去吗  -请进
- Can we come in? - Oh, come on in.
-她在那里  -她好漂亮
- Oh, there she is. - Oh, she's so beautiful.
来吧
Here.
天啊  她太美了
Oh, my God. She's amazing.
我很高兴你们喝醉后上了床
Oh, I'm so glad you guys got drunk and had sex.
太不可思议了  前一分钟她还在你肚子里
It's incredible. I mean, one minute she's inside you...
而47小时后  她就出生了
...and then 47 hours later, here she is.
她看起来好真实
She looks so real.
你们了解我的意思
You know what I mean.
-好了  轮到我了  -菲比阿姨
- Okay, my turn. My turn. - Aunt Phoebe.
宝贝  你好可爱
Oh, baby. Oh, you're so cute!
我可以捏碎你的小脑袋
Oh, I could squeeze your little head.
我不会那么做的
I won't.
亲爱的  怎么了
Honey, what's the matter?
没事  我只是禁不住要哭
Nothing. I just can't stop crying.
医生说这很正常  都是荷尔蒙害的
The doctor said it's completely normal, with all the hormones,
而且你一直都没睡觉
plus you're sleep-deprived.
你们也都没睡
So. You guys are all sleep-deprived.
我怎么没见你们因为拖鞋穿错脚就哭哭啼啼
I don't see you weeping because you put your slippers on the wrong feet.
天啊
Oh, God.
-现在怎么了  -我又想起那事了
- What's the matter now? - I was reliving it.
你们帮她取好名字了吗
Do you know what you're gonna call her yet?
等一下  她不是叫小姑娘吗
Wait, it's not gonna be Baby Girl?
我觉得那个名字很有创意
I thought that was so original.
事实上我们正在考虑两个名字
Actually, we've narrowed it down to two names.
你知道吗  两个名字我都很喜欢
And you know what? I love them both.
你选哪个  我们就用哪个
So why don't you just pick one, and that'll be it.
好吧  大伙们...
Okay. Everyone...
她是伊莎贝拉
...this is Isabella.
-嗨  伊莎贝拉  -嗨
- Hi, Isabella! - Hi.
怎么了
What?
听着不像她的名字
That's not her name.
抱歉  她感觉上不像伊莎贝拉
I'm sorry, she just doesn't feel like an Isabella.
-另一个名字是什么  -迪莉拉
- What was the other one? - Delilah.
太棒了  突然间她就成了圣经时代的妓女
Oh, great! Suddenly she sounds like a biblical whore.
那我们还是叫她小姑娘吧
So I guess we're back to Baby Girl.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
没关系  你们会想到好名字的
It's okay. You'll find a name.
你说得倒容易
Easy for you to say.
你已经知道你的孩子要叫什么名字了
You already know what your kids' names will be.
-是吗  -我14岁时就帮他们取好了名字
- You do? - Yeah, I had them picked out since I was 14.
不  你的宝宝会以点心
Oh, no, it's gonna be named after some snack
或烘烤食物的名字来命名吧
or baked good, isn't it?
告诉我们你想了什么名字
Well, tell us, what are they?
好吧  如果是男孩的话就叫丹尼尔
Okay. If it's a boy, it's Daniel.
-如果是女孩呢  -我不想说
- And if it's a girl? - I don't wanna say.
少来了  告诉我们  我们不会抢走的
Oh, stop. Tell us. We're not gonna want it.
好吧  她叫艾玛
Okay. It's Emma.
艾玛
Emma.
看吧  我不喜欢
See, I don't want it.
-拿去吧  -什么
- Take it. - What?
她很适合叫艾玛
She's clearly an Emma.
亲爱的  但你很喜欢那个名字
Oh, honey, but you love that name.
对  但我更爱你
Yeah, but I love you more.
而且什么名字都跟宾不配  所以我是死定了
Besides, nothing goes with Bing. So I'm screwed.
艾伦·利普曼·古拉尼克
Aaron Lipman-Guralnick
要跟他未来的新娘打个招呼
would like to say hello to his future bride.
看到他会说不出话来  对吧
Wow, he kind of takes your breath away, doesn't he?
他是个好男人
He's a keeper.
-你觉得如何  -我很好
- How you feeling? - Oh, I'm fine.
我真的很佩服你所做的一切
Can I just say I really admire what you're doing.
你要自己抚养她
Just raising her all alone.
我不是一个人  我有罗斯
I'm not doing it alone. I have Ross.
现在是的
Sure. Now.
如果他结识别人结了婚  到时你该怎么办
But what happens when he meets somebody else and gets married?
他会离婚的  他可是罗斯
Well, then he gets a divorce. It's Ross.
我得告诉你  瑞秋  听珍妮丝的话
I'm telling you, Rachel, listen to Janice.
男人都说他们会陪你
They all say they're gonna be there,
但他们会成立自己的家庭
until they start their real family.
罗斯不会那么做的
That's never gonna happen with Ross.
以前我也相信我前夫不会那样
That's what I thought about my first husband.
现在如果孩子能跟她爸  双胞胎和隆胸小姐
Now, I'm lucky if my kid gets to spend a weekend with her father...
共度周末  我就谢天谢地了
and the twins and little Miss New Boobs.
真的吗
Really?
我也不想跟你说这种话
I hate to be the one to say it...
但你们两个人得靠自己
...but, honey, you two are on your own.
这个...  你知道的  这...
Well, that's... You know, that's...
我们已经单独相处了20分钟
We've been alone for the last 20 minutes
没出什么问题
and we're doing okay.
也许我们不必靠自己
Besides, you know what? Maybe we won't be alone.
因为最近我跟罗斯之间擦出了火花
Because lately things have been happening between me and Ross.
我来医院前  我们还接了吻
And right before I went into labor, we had this kiss. You know?
或许我们会再续前缘
So it might be the beginning of something.
-嗨  珍妮丝  -嗨
- Hey, Janice. - Oh, hi.
这个小家伙是谁
Who's this little guy?
-艾伦  那是你未来的岳父  -不
- Say hello to Aaron, your future son-in-law. - Oh, no.
-我让你们一家人好好独处  -好吧
- I'm gonna leave you three alone. - Okay.
天啊  你看到那孩子的鼻子了吗
Man, you see the kid on that nose?
你知道我刚刚在想什么吗
You know what I was thinking about?
我们出门前的那个吻
That kiss before we left the apartment.
那不只是普通的一吻  对吧
That was something, huh?
对  没错
Yeah. Yeah, it really was.
但我们得小心点
But we... We gotta be careful.
我们...你知道的  我们不能让历史重演
We... You know, we can't let that happen again, you know?
对
Right.
我们不希望重蹈覆辙  对吧
We don't want to go down that road, do we?
对  所以我才会跟你提这件事
No, of course not. That's why I brought it up.
医院没有汽水吗
They didn't have any sodas?
天啊  对不起
Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
我忙着跟护士说话  完全忘了这事
I was talking to this nurse. Completely forgot.
现在就已经开始了
And so it begins.
她在里面吗
She in there?
对  护士正把她放在床上  那就是她
Yeah. She's putting her down now. That's her.
快看艾玛
Look. Look at Emma.
我不知道她长得更像你还是瑞秋
I can't decide who she looks more like, you or Rachel.
什么  开什么玩笑
Oh, what, are you kidding?
她美极了  完全遗传瑞秋
She's gorgeous! It's all Rachel.
对不起  这是我最后一次问你
I'm sorry. For the last time,
你们两个为什么不结婚
why aren't you two together again?
我知道因为你们没有到那个程度
No, I know. Because you're not in that place.
其实也没什么  但事实上你们绝对到了
Which would be fine, except you totally are.
情况很复杂  好吗
It's complicated, okay?
对  这话没错
Yeah, that's true.
你一直都爱着她  你们生了一个孩子
You love her, you always have, you have a child together.
谁知道你们该不该结婚
There's no right answer.
我们曾经交往过  后来分手
Look, we've been together. And then apart.
复合后又分手
And then together, and then apart.
现在我们生了一个孩子
And now we have a baby.
如果我们又复合  结果还是分手
It's just, if we got together again and it didn't work out...
我不能对艾玛做那种事
I could never do that to Emma.
她来到这个世界上  觉得每件事都...
I mean, she came into this world thinking everything...
我怎么也这样了
Now me.
难道他们在水里放了催泪剂吗
What, do they put something in the water in this place?
瑞秋跟我现在过得很好
It's just, Rachel and I, we're doing really well right now.
我知道
I know. I know. I know.
如果你想更进一步  可能会毁掉现在的美好
I know. If you try to make it more, you might wreck it.
-没错  -对
- Yeah, exactly. - Right.
或者你可以得到你从15岁开始就梦想的生活
Or you might get everything you've wanted since you were 15.
我看到一个女人同时在喂双胞胎母乳
I saw a woman breast-feeding twins at the same time.
真的很像怪胎秀
It is like a freak show up here.
-怎么了  -没事
- What's the matter? - Nothing.
怎么了
What is it? Hey.
真的没事  我...
Really, it's nothing. I'm...
瑞秋  别这样  怎么了
Rach, come on. What?
我一直在想我跟宝宝要怎么独自生活下去
I've just been thinking about how my baby and I are gonna be all alone.
你在说什么  罗斯呢
What are you talking about alone? What about Ross?
拜托  他会成立自己的家庭
Please. He'll be with his real family.
双胞胎跟隆胸小姐
The twins and little Miss New Boobs.
难道我瞅了那女人这么久  这都啥时候的事
Okay, how long was I watching that woman?
我只是说...
I'm just saying that, you know...
有一天罗斯会认识别的女人
...someday Ross is gonna meet somebody...
他会拥有自己的生活
...and he's gonna have his own life.
对吧
Right?
你说得对
Yeah, I guess so.
我没想到我要独自抚养这个宝宝
I just never thought I'd be raising this baby all by myself.
真的很傻吧
That's pretty dumb, huh?
你得听我说  听着
Hey, you listen to me. Listen to me.
你永远都不会孤立无援
You are never, ever gonna be alone.
我发誓我不会让那种事发生
Okay? I promise I won't let that happen.
乔伊
Joey.
亲爱的  没有你我该怎么办
Oh, sweetie, what would I do without you?
你不必担心  好吗
You don't have to worry about that, okay?
你能再帮我拿盒面纸来吗
Could you grab me my other box of tissues?
-就在罗斯的外套下面  -没问题
- They're right on the chair under Ross' coat. - Sure.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
乔伊
Joey?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
好吧
Okay.
-刚刚简直太销魂了  -我知道
- That was amazing.  - I know.
你知不知道我们很可能
Hey, do you realize that
已经永远地改写了我们的生活
we may have just changed our lives forever?
我们可能已经开始组建了自己的家庭
We may have started our family.
九个月后我们可能会来这里...
In nine months we could be here...
生下我们的孩子
...having our own baby.
如果不行  我们就得在桶上做了
And if not, we got to do it on a bucket.